<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Rahil Arora</title>
 <link href="http://rahilarora.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://rahilarora.com/"/>
 <updated>2015-01-10T16:44:50-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://rahilarora.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Rahil Arora</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Hello world!</title>
   <link href="http://rahilarora.com/2015/01/07/hello-world/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://rahilarora.com/2015/01/07/hello-world</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hola amigos!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just a cliché &lt;em&gt;hello world!&lt;/em&gt; post. To know about me and why I&amp;#39;ve started this website, please visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rahilarora.com/about/&quot;&gt;about section&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to start my blog with a technical (security related) post, but I&amp;#39;ve not been able to read anything interesting, as I&amp;#39;m currently enjoying most of my time with my family in India. Anyways, I&amp;#39;ll just give a quick introduction to what you can expect from the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is an attempt to improve my knowledge and writing skills, by contributing something useful, back to the security community. It will also act as a useful resource for the beginners who are interested in topics such as Cryptography, Application Security and Network Security. I will try to explain things/concepts in simple terms in order to target different types of readers at different levels of understanding. However, I beleive that the posts and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rahilarora.com/useful_resources/&quot;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;#39;ll be sharing, will be of great use to current graduate/undergrad students, who are willing to pursue a career in Security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:contact@rahilarora.com&quot;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt;, if you want me to share something specific or need any advice/help. Please feel free to do the same or leave a comment below, if you have any advice for me or any comment regarding anything on this website. &lt;em&gt;We are all here to learn. That&amp;#39;s what life is all about!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned...&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
